What is this?
Am I getting jealous?
This can't be, Carmela!
Erase, erase.
By the way...
Helena agreed to
go out with me.
We're going to the
field of roses.
Do you want to come?
No, thanks.
I have lots of things
to do at home.
Good luck to the two of you.
Good luck.
Please accept my heart
that only belongs to you.
Oh, Juanito. Since we're already here...
Why don't you sing a song
to Miss Helena as well?
Carmelita,
Explain yourself to me.
Juanito and I have decided
to do something
to stop the wedding.
I am still in love with Leandro.
Carmela, why are you smiling?
Are you looking for this?
My love,
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
I am hoping we can
rekindle our relationship.
And if you and Juanito succeed
in stopping the wedding...
I hope you open up your heart again...
for Leandro.
I hope you open up your heart again
I will not give up on you, my love.
I am hoping that you
will give me a chance.
Is this a song or a poem?
Gosh!
It's already midnight
but he's still bugging me.
Miss...
There's something I want to give you.
I did not forget
your strict instruction
since Mr. Leandro left.
You asked me to dispose of all his letters.
Even those that are to be delivered.
I apologize, Miss,
but I didn't throw all of it.
I thought there would come a time
when you would need to read his letters.
So that you may have a better decision.
Miss,
it's not yet too late.
It seems like Mr. Leandro
doesn't plan to give up.
I hope you won't give up as easily.
If Leandro didn't write
what his fault was,
I don't know what I'll do.
I think I'll be reading
throughout the night.
17th of January,
Year 1891.
My dear Carmelita.
How are you?
Have you read the letters I've sent you?
You might still be mad at me.
I cannot blame you.
I want you to understand that
it is my dream to join the army.
Aside from Father's wishes
for me to follow in his footsteps,
it is also my own desire.
I'm touched by Leandro's
efforts and principles.
He truly loves Carmelita.
Maybe Carmelita just acted dramatically
Carmelita...
I hope you'll give me a chance.
For me to prove how much I care for you.
I know it's not my place to forgive
on behalf of Carmelita,
but this is the only way
to fulfill the mission of
stopping the wedding.
Don't worry anymore.
I forgive you.
Are you saying
you're not mad at me anymore?
Just promise me that
you will not hurt me again.
Oh...
Apologies.
- I thought that...
- It's fine.
I forgave him but that doesn't me
I get to be his girlfriend.
And...
what if my Father and Mother catch us?
They'll get upset,
right?
Carmelita,
our families are close to one another.
They are fully aware of our relationship.
I was about to ask your parents
for your hand in marriage.
But you became angry with me
when you learned that I'm leaving.
Gosh, if only Carmelita
didn't act like such a brat,
Leandro and her would still be together.
Juanito wouldn't be dragged into it
and they wouldn't have died.
Most importantly,
I wouldn't be transported into the past!
But don't you worry.
I will do everything
for us to be together again.
Leandro.
Do you really know me that well?
Of course, Carmelita.
If you love a person,
you know all the
important things about her.
What's my favorite food?
Vegetable stew.
Seriously? I don't even eat vegetables.
Is Carmelita a vegetarian? Gosh...
How about my hobbies?
Reading books.
Doing embroidery.
Dance?
Carinosa.
And Tinikling.
Games?
Is this a trick question, Carmelita?
You don't like playing games.
You're always cooped up in your house.
What do I fear?
You're afraid of losing me.
So, pick-up lines are
popular even then, huh?
Apologies. I was just joking.
You are afraid of bugs and beasts.
General.
Miss Carmelita.
What are you doing here?
Mr. Leandro.
He's just keeping me company on my walk.
Miss Carmelita,
my brother Juanito wrote to me.
He's asking why you are
not answering his letters.
Angelito,
it is not right for you to
interrupt adult conversations.
I was just really busy
with a lot of things,
that's why I wasn't able to reply.
You really do seem very busy right now.
Don't take it the wrong way,
but you will be in trouble
if anyone puts malice on the two of you.
Having said that...
would you rather just walk with us instead?
There's no need.
Our carriages will soon
come any moment now.
Very well.
We'll go ahead.
I don't want to be late
on my journey to Manila.
General Sergio doesn't know about
the plan to stop the wedding.
He might tell Don Alejandro!
I'm doomed!
I'll prepare your bath before we go.
Your family has been invited
to the birthday of the
Governor General in Manila.
Problem solved!
I can avoid Leandro with this.
And Don Alejandro would not suspect me.
I'll help you.
Do not bother yourself, Miss.
I'm sure
your Aunt Rosario will
be pleased to see you.
Aunt Rosario?
Yes.
Your mother's sister.
Her family has been invited as well.
Oh my Gosh!
I'll meet a relative who knows Carmelita.
What if she asks me about books?
Gosh! I need to do something about this!
This is the first time
you'll be able to attend
the Governor-General's birthday,
isn't it, Carmelita?
Sorry.
I forgot that you don't have a voice.
Shouting nonstop to lose my voice
was actually a smart strategy.
Less talk, fewer mistakes.
Ladies and Gentlemen!
Tonight we celebrate
not only with good food,
but also with good company.
- Cheers!
Music please.
Let us dance!
OMG! I missed this! It's time to party!
Carmelita., Dance appropriately.
Oops, I forgot about that.
They may have lived in a different time,
and we came from different eras...
one thing is for sure.
From today, they're a part of my life too.
Maestro, may I request
the traditional Cariñosa?
We invite the couples to the center
of the dance floor.
Cariñosa!
Miss Carmelita?
May I dance the Cariñosa with you?
Focus, Carmela!
You must be sharp in copying the dance.
You must not get
distracted by Juanito's eyes.
Juanito is really good at dancing.
Thank you for letting me be with you
during your favorite dance.
You were wonderful,
Carmelita and Juanito.
I am glad to meet you, Mr. Juanito.
I heard so many things about
your handsome face and brilliant mind.
And you are such a gentleman.
That is not true.
Maybe the person who told you that
were giving too much compliments.
Mr. Juanito,
are you saying that my niece
over-praised you?
Wait,
I never said that Juanito is handsome,
brilliant, and a gentleman.
Apologies, Juanito.
Carmelita lost her voice
since we left San Alfonso.
Why, what happened to your voice?
Wondeful! wonderful!
I am left speechless!
It's unfortunate Helena
wasn't able to come.
I heard she was sick.
By the way, my friends,
my only son has returned.
Leandro cut his training short.
But he is in Cavite now
and would not be able to come.
Why did Leandro went
home earlier that expected?
An important thing was stolen from him.
He has to take it back
before it's too late.
Is that Juanito?
What is he doing here in Laguna?
Doesn't he have classes?
Carmelita,
what's happening to you?
You look like you've seen a ghost.
I think I saw Juanito.
Can I catch up to him?
Miss Carmelita.
What are you doing here?
Who are those candles for?
I wanted to pay my
respects to a kind family
who became close to me.
I heard what happened
to them just this morning.
There were witnesses who heard
their screams a few nights ago.
Their whole family was brutally murdered.
And their corpses were thrown
in the cemetery for criminals.
What was their crime?
They were accused of a crime
I know they could never commit.
It's impossible for Nestor
to steal a bag of rice.
And Trinidad would never say
anything false against other people.
Killing their five children
was truly brutal as well.
Trinidad's family was murdered?
I promised Trinidad and Nestor...
That I will not stop until I discover
who had them murdered.
It is important to recognize and address
the concerns of our workers.
Dear Diary...
I hope my suspicion is wrong.
But I think Don Alejandro is involved
in the murder of Trinidad's family.
Carmelita!
We're gonna be late on
the road to San Alfonso!
Where is your sister?
We have to go!
I won't come.
What's wrong with you?
What are you saying?
Is there a problem, Carmelita?
Why are you suddenly
acting this way, Carmelita?
Doña Rosario,
did something happen
while you were out last time?
Nothing, Don Alejandro.
My gut is always right, so
don't bother covering it up.
I've learned my lesson,
When i said that it was Miss Trinidad
who asked for favor
Something bad happened to her family.
And now, if I mention Juanito,
he might get in danger next.
Answer me, Carmelita.
Did something happen?
How can you murder Trinidad's whole family?
Carmelita, watch what you're saying.
Carmelita,
don't you ever talk
that way to your Father.
I know that rumor is going around,
but I didn't expect my own daughter...
To believe in lies that were made
to ruin her Father's reputation.
If you don't want to be
around me, I understand.
Stay here if you must.
Thank you.
I will go ahead.
Thank you very much.
God bless you.
Mother Olivia!
He's so vile!
We can't do anything about it.
If that's what's destined to happen.
Let's just pray for their souls.
Is that the way it's gonna be?
I could've prevented
a terrible thing from happening, but...
But I did nothing.
That isn't your mission here, dear.
Focus your attention there.
If you continue meddling,
things will only get worse.
Remember this.
You are Carmelita.
She will never talk back to her father.
Unlike what you did.
Stay here in my room
until Helena gets better.
Josefina will be staying in Natasha's room.
I'm just wondering.
If I'm here now inside Carmelita's body…
Where is the real Carmelita?
She's here.
You're holding her in your hands.
Her fate is up to you.
Oh my gosh!
Is Carmelita inside there?!
In the diary?
Do not be afraid, dear.
Her mind and soul rest in this diary.
She can't hurt you.
Before you even came to this time…
She already knew that you would come.
To help her.
Before Carmelita took her own life…
She came to the church first.
And prayed.
Juanito has been dead for a week by then.
I was also praying at the church too.
And I heard her prayer.
I followed her out of the church.
Carmelita!
If you will strike a deal with me…
You may be able to change
the fate of Juanito and yourself.
By rewriting the…
Events that happened in
the past and changing them.
I can stop Juanito's death?
Not you.
But a woman
born into the family
of your sister, Maria.
She will be born with
your striking likeness.
She will rewrite your fate.
Using this diary.
She is the person
destined to change
your fate and Juanito's.
And what's the catch?
You need to disappear.
So that time may continue to pass.
I am ready to die if that's what it takes.
You aren't going to die, dear.
Your soul with just
sleep inside the diary.
I'd rather wait years
for the destined woman.
And forget Juanito.
Than letting him die.
And be haunted by our
memories for the rest of my life.
And my love for him.
Wait, Mother Olivia.
You said that if I finish my mission,
Carmelita will wake up.
But she won't remember anything?
But what about the sacrifices
that she made for Juanito?
She will just wake up
like nothing happened?
She will forget about Juanito?
Why do you concern yourself with it?
You know the truth of Carmelita's
unrequited love towards Juanito.
Ouch. I forgot that this
is an unrequited love.
The moment Carmelita first saw
Juanito
during Helena's birthday party…
She immediately fell in love with him.
Even though she knew
that Juanito likes Helena…
Carmelita still chose to love him.
OMG.
Carmelita met Juanito
during Helena's party?
But why did I met Juanito at UST
and then we were able
to talk in the convent?
I stopped you that night.
But you didn't listen.
That is why I don't know
how the next events will unfold.
It seems like
you already changed
what is supposed to happen.
The one who will kill Juanito…
Is it still the same person?
Why didn't I read the diary
when it was first given to me?
Then I would have a
clue who's behind it all.
Maybe the situation has changed.
But the people behind Juanito's murder…
I'm sure it's still the same people.
Them?
So there's more than one?
One cannot fulfill things
without the help of others.
You know, I think Don
Alejandro is a part of this.
If he can order to
murder Trinidad's family…
It's not impossible for him
to murder Juanito as well.
Carmela...
Be careful with your assumptions.
It's not enough that you
complete your mission.
You must also ensure the
safety of the Montecarlos family.
Especially Maria.
You are from her lineage.
It means that if Maria
fails to bear a child,
Grandma Carmina, Mommy,
Jenny, and Emily and I
will not exist in the future!
I heard Carmelita went back to the convent.
And that she and Don
Alejandro aren't in good terms.
I may be the reason.
I told her about the
murder of Trinidad's family.
And she suspects that
Don Alejandro is behind it.
Is it true?
I can't tell for sure.
But I am worried about Carmelita.
Are you just worried or
are you starting to have feelings for her?
If you're in love with her
you need to be true to yourself.
And to Helena as well.
That I'm sure she's in love with you.
Juanito...
You need to be true to who you love.
But before you could do that…
You need to be honest with yourself first.
Honest with what you feel.
You need to talk to Carmelita and Helena.
And tell them the truth.
Mother Olivia's revelations
were so over the top.
I'm more stressed than ever.
Good thing I found this
in Aunt Rosario's house.
I'm not the type to get drunk easily, but
this wine's no joke!
I can't!
Carmelita!
Wake up!
If Father and Mother learn that you drink,
they will surely reprimand you!
Add that to the punishment you'll get
since alcohol is forbidden here.
Carmelita!
I never imagine you drink alcohol.
What would Mr. Juanito say?
That the woman he's about to marry
is out of her mind alcoholic?
What does Juanito have
to do about me drinking?
I don't care about what he thinks of me.
He can judge me all he wants.
Juanito was the one to took you back here.
- What?!
- You were too drunk and…
You were saying all these weird things.
How did he know where I am?!
He arrived here last night
but Mother Olivia
refused to let him enter.
That's why I helped him.
I told him where he can find you.
In the kitchen.
There at the back, at the balcony.
Why did you tell him?
Because I support your marriage to him!
And I didn't know you were drinking!
You're so embarrasing, girl!
Carmelita?
What are you doing here?
I want to give you something.
Do you like it, Miss Carmela?
How did Juanito know my real name?
What is this?
Do you remember the day I left San Alfonso?
When I told you to meet me at the port?
Because I want to give you something.
Is this it?
I was supposed to give you
another one at the pier.
But I thought…
That name suits you more
because of how naughty you are.
Is he saying Carmelita
sounds fair and lovely,
but Carmela sounds naughty? Crazy!
What are you trying to say?
Don't you remember?
Remember what?
Do I need to remember anything?
Everything that happened to us last night.
So it's true! Josefina
wasn't messing with me.
I know a way to help someone remember
when they've forgotten something.
It's like this…
On the count of three, you'll remember…
One...
Two...
Three.
I'm just kidding.
Don't force yourself to recall it.
It's better this way.
You might avoid seeing me.
Someone actually told me that
when it comes to embarrassing things…
It's better to pretend
as if nothing happened.
Come.
I'll put it on you.
It adds to your beauty…
When you wear expensive jewelry
made with silver and gold.
But I'm aware you prefer gifts
made with one's own effort.
That's why I thought of giving this to you.
This was the other
necklace I ought to give you.
I wanted to give it you at the pier.
But you didn't come.
I'm sorry.
I failed to wake up early.
That's why I couldn't come.
If he only knew how much
I prepared for that day.
But the things is, Helena
was going there first.
I went there early.
I waited for you.
Speaking of Helena,
she told me she's going to
respond to Juanito's proposal.
What happened with you and Helena?
I was already aboard
the ship when she arrived.
I actually thought it was you who came.
Even the letters I've sent
you were left unanswered.
So, Helena wasn't able
to tell Juanito her feelings?
Yeah, actually…
it was Maria and Mother.
We're always going out.
I forgot to reply to your letters.
I'm sorry.
You forgot to wake up early…
You also forgot to reply to my letters.
You don't remember
anything from last night.
What else did you forgot?
I promise…
I won't ever forget anymore.
I hope you won't forget…
That no matter what happens…
And where ever I may be…
I'll wait for you.
Oh no!
I can't fall in love
with Juanito!
Miss, what are you
doing here?
What is it to you
if I want to get drunk?!
I don't even care!
Miss Carmelita, let's go.
Her name's Cristeta.
A man wearing black came.
He told me I was safe.
But I have to say that
Don Alejandro was
the mastermind.
Don't you love
reading books?
I am feeling dizzy.
Do you know
that feeling...
It feels like I can't read
for a few months.
I am yours and you are mine.
That is what's written
in the stars.
Why are you two
alone in here?!
- We're not doing anything wrong!
- You're misunderstanding this.
Did Juanito gave you
a letter for me?
He stopped sending me letters since he
came back to Manila.
Mr. Leandro.